## Jesús Salazar Sedano

(+51) 947816817, GMT-5 jesus.salazar@pucp.pe https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriel-salazar-sedano/ https://github.com/cubicles https://cubicles.github.io

Data Scientist with 3+ years of experience in the Software Development area providing IT solutions for the mining and banking industries formerly as Project Analyst and currently as a Data Engineer. Fluent in Python, SQL, R, and PowerApps while working under agile environments using collaborative tools such as Git, Bitbucket, Jira and Confluence. Electronics Engineer Bachelor currently pursuing a Ms Degree in Computer Science. Interested in Research, Machine Learning, Microelectronic Systems and Academic Teaching. Working parallely as TA for PUCP every spring semester.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Bluetab Solutions, an IBM Company, Data Engineer — Jul, 2021 - Present

Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exerc. Irure dolor in reprehend incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua

- Participated in Big Data projects by developing PySpark Notebooks and Python scripts for applied data processing and productivization
- Contributed to ETL workflows by documenting functional/non functional requirements and workflows

#### Banco Falabella Perú, Project Analyst — Feb, 2020 - Jun, 2021

Project Analyst for the TI-HR area. Worked as both analyst / developer in Web Development / ERP / Data Analysis projects.

- Developed "App Gestión Humana FIF", a web/mobile application using PowerApps and PowerAutomate, containing over 5 modules (Assistance, Compensation, Benefits, COVID Checklist, Work+Anniversary) for over 10.000+ People in 3 countries (Chile, Peru, Colombia) in Falabella
- Participated in the implementation of SAP Employee Central as key functional user for the IT-HR area, documenting
  the functional requirements for over 10 workflows around the enterprise cloud ERP.
- Professional Intern working alongside IT and HR for analysis and implementation of Web/Mobile applications and ERP-cloud based solutions.

## Hochschild Mining PLC, Professional Intern - Sep, 2018 - Sep, 2019

Professional Intern working alongside IT and HR for analysis and implementation of Web/Mobile applications and ERP-cloud based solutions.

- Contributed to the Security and Safety mobile application development overseeing the implementation of 2 new modules (OTO, Transportation Reporting) by analyzing, designing, testing and placing in production the in-house applications (iOs / Android).
- Participated in the implementation of SAP SuccessFactors as Key Functional User. Worked alongside the HR and TI team documenting the functional requirements.
- Professional Intern working alongside IT and HR for analysis and implementation of Web/Mobile applications and ERP-cloud based solutions.

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### Laboratory Teaching Assistant, Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú — Mar, 2018 - Jul, 2021

Teaching Assistant of the following courses:

- 1IEE01 Microelectronics (Spring Semester: 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021)
- IEE209 Electronic Physics (Fall Semester: 2018)

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL, C++, C, Java

Frameworks and Tools: Spark, Notebooks, PowerBI, PostgreSQL, Jenkins, Git, Jira, Confluence, PowerApps

Languages: English, Fluent IELTS 7.5; Spanish, Native;

### **EDUCATION**

# Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnología – Lima, Perú

Master of Science, Computer Science, 2021 - 2022

## Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú – Lima, Perú

Bachelor of Science, Electronics Engineer, 2012 - 2017, Upper Third, Microelectronics Group